

Designation
Software Developer

+91-8097508703 arsalaanprof@gmail.com 4B/603, Patliputra Nagar, New Link Road, Oshiwara, Jogeshwari(W), Mumbai – 400102. linkedin.com/in/arsalaan-ansari/ github.com/Arsalaan11

PERSONAL

STATEMENT

A self-motivated, organized professional with an analytical mindset and a keen eye for details, who has a deep-rooted inclination towards application. To seek a good challenging position in a company where I can prove myself and utilize my potential to ultimately become a successful professional in my area of expertise.

WORK **EXPERIENCE**

TECHSEVIN LLP. / SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

August 2018 – August 2020

- Developed object oriented programming based projects with languages like PHP, JavaScript, Html, CSS and the use of Framework like Laravel, Magento 2 and Angular in order to develop full-fledged E-Commerce websites.
- Main tasks involves web crawling or third party APIs which provides the detailed information about the particular event happening across the world. The data are fetched in JSON or XML data format it was parsed and saved in the database repository.
- Analyzed and designed the relational database architecture using MySQL based protocols, wrote application in E-commerce based architecture and collaborated with other developers to identify and alleviate number of bugs and errors in the software.
- Worked on integration of SEO and speed optimization of website to reduce loads on the website that takes a lot of logging and report the records for OPS processes. Maintain a complete modular system for logs of employees working in the company like their attendance, salary, leaves etc.

WCITIES CONTENT SOLUTION PVT. LTD. / SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

January 2018 – June 2018

- Implementation on live website EVENTSEEKER.COM. This involves Full Stack Development using various technologies.
- Technologies used like PHP, MYSQL JAVASCRIPT where the website showed events across the globe and was responsible for fetching data from various partners.
- The validation of login page was enhanced feature added in the system. During the internship was given multiple role while working on the various terminology.
- Implemented different process on partners in order to fetch the data in the system and get the information being rendered on the live website.

PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN / SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

- Project website www.seniority.com

 A live retail store website that has access to all the products that can be ordered from the website directly B2C.

 A website developed using various technology like PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, Magento 2.
- Project website www.sultan-center.com
 A web application developed in order to process the orders in the system. It was only for the company use for the employees
 A website developed using various technology like PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, Laravel, Angular2+.
- Website www.eventseeker.com
 A live website that will showcase all the events happening around on the globe.
 A website developed using various technology like PHP, JAVASCRIPT, MYSQL.

EDUCATIONAL **QUALIFICATIONS**

THAKUR INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT STUDIES CAREER DEVELOPMENT & RESEARCH

July 2015 - July 2018

(MUMBAI UNIVERSITY) / MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION

7.58 GPA

VALIA C.L. COLLEGE OF SCIENCE

July 2012 – March 2015

(MUMBAI UNIVERSITY) BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (INFORMATION TECH)

75.25%

TECHNICAL **SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING

- HTML/CSS
- PHP
- C++
- JAVASCRIPT

FRAMEWORK

- Magento 2
- Laravel 5.5
- ANGULAR 2+

PLATFORM

- Windows
- Linux (Ubuntu/Cent OS)

HOBBIES

- Football
- Swimming

ACHIEVEMENTS/

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Stood 5th in Valia College (BSc IT) in 2015.
- Won 3rd prize in Quiz Competition in event held at college fest.
- Won 2nd prize in Synape event held in TIMSCDR.
- Cultural Secretary of Cultural Committee for the year 2013-2014 and 2014-15 (Valia College)
- Organizing Committee member for the College Fest during academic year 2015-2016 and 2016-17 (Thakur College)

PERSONAL

DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH: 17th November, 1994

GENDER: Male

• NATIONALITY: Indian

LANGUAGES: English, Hindi, Urdu.